Deepak Padukone Manjunath

♣ (he/him/his) • Authorised to work in the UK 🔀 deepakpadukone20@live.com 📞 +44 7824077651

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/deepak-padukone-m

PROFILE

10+ years experience in Software Engineering, developing products in the EdTech, Digital Automotive, and FinTech industries with an innate ability to quickly adapt to emerging technologies. I am studying MBA to improve my business skills, where I specialise in Innovation Management, Digital Business, and Project Management. I am considering transitioning into Product Management to leverage my technical expertise and business acumen.

EDUCATION

MBA - General Management

University of Nottingham Business School Activities and societies:

- MBA Alumni Ambassador 2022
- Dissertation (Currently working): Quensus Limited Digital Marketing strategy for an entrepreneurial tech firm.
- Pay review and proposed roadmap for implementation for all Staff (Phase 1) for the University of Warwick; presented to Senior Management of Deloitte
- Worked in a team of 8 to aid a local charity **Northampton Hope Centre** in developing a Marketing and Revenue Generation Plan;
- Collaborated as a team to introduce a tech-based solution 'Revive' to India's agricultural sector to reduce food waste; presented a business pitch to reuse 'food produces' to a new B2B value co-creation.

Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Science

Visvesvaraya Technological University

Jun 2007 - Jun 2011 Bangalore, India

Sep 2021 - Sep 2022

Nottingham,

United Kingdom

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Cyber Security Engineer - Opensource and Automation

- Lead the product development pipeline for Cybersecurity Engineering Automation (DevOps) and Open-Source development. Responsible for gathering requirements from stakeholders, communicating product vision to senior management, and ensuring product release from inception to release.
- Hands-on experience in working in a scrum/agile practices environment. Coordinated projects/products across several global teams (across the US, the UK and India).
- Architected and built CyberVision Dashboard, Endpoint Dashboard to visualize the security posture of Visa Cybersecurity, collated API data of multiple security tools like Forcepoint, McAfee Total Protection, Sentinel One, Microsoft Defender for Endpoint, Carbon Black, Tanium, Netskope, Invincea, Activ Client, etc. Exposed to RedHat Ansible, Splunk, ELK stack (Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana).

Tech: JavaScript, Angular 8, SCSS, HTML5, Python, Node.js, Flask, Scripting, Ansible, D3.js, Elastic, Jira, Balsamiq

Informatica Inc

Senior Software Engineer - Enterprise Data Catalog

- Responsible for Core Metadata products at Informatica including product development of ever-evolving products in Informatica Metadata suites like Enterprise Data Catalog, underlying Metadata Platform, CLAIRE, Data Profiling and Domain Discovery.
- Collaborated with cross-functional team members to analyse potential system solutions based on evolving technical requirements.
- Improved and expanded project platforms using Object-oriented JavaScript to develop rich User Interfaces.
- Explored and developed chrome plugin which works on Tableau for insight on Data governance and cataloging for B2B customers to make insightful data-driven decisions. Tech: JavaScript, React 16, HTML5, SCSS, Java, Google Chrome APIs, D3. js, yFiles, Node. js, Apace Lucene, Jenkins

Jan 2019 - Aug 2021 Bangalore, India

Jun 2015 - Jan 2019 Bangalore, India

Ness Technologies

Senior Software Engineer - CDK Global Automotive CRM

May 2014 – Jun 2015 Bangalore, India

- Conceptualize, architect, and develop high-performance, robust UI features for automotive manufacturer and dealership online marketing presence (websites et al)
- Drive product innovation, development, enhancement, and refactoring across teams, evangelizing design patterns, best practices, and a do-it-right approach
- Engage in code reviews and pair programming methods to produce more stable implementations
- Train and mentor colleagues of all experience levels
- Built unit, integration, functional and acceptance level tests to provide QA support of continuous deployment with the intent to fail fast in error or regression scenarios
- Seek to apply and improve the incorporation of Agile methodologies (Scrum, Kanban, iterative development, etc) in day-to-day activities

Tech: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, Angular.js, Java, Jenkins, Cassandra

Epiance Software Pvt. Ltd

Software Engineer - Epiplex Learning Management System

- Delivered solutions for EpiLearn, Epitracker and Epiplex Content management systems to provide businesses with detailed digital
- recordkeeping capability.
- Gathered and defined user requirements to develop clear specifications for creating well-organized project plans.
- Completed projects in alignment with the target before deadlines building B2C products, with a wide reach user base.

Tech: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, YUI, jQuery, ASP.net, SQL, Microsoft Access

Jun 2011 – May 2014 Bangalore, India

SKILLS

JavaScript

Angular 8, React 16, Redux, D3.js, jQuery, Node.js, Next.js, Jamstack

Agile Development

Jira, Fisheye, Crucible, Confluence, Product Management, Strategic Thinking

Python

Flask, Tornado, Numpy, SciPy

Web Development

HTML, SCSS, CSS, UI/UX, Data visualisation, ASP.Net, Web Services

Database

Elastic, Firestore, SQL, Oracle, GCP

Others

Java, Golang, Serverless Webapps, Webkit, Balsamiq, Microsoft Powerpoint and Excel

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

Kannada

French